Okay. Raj...
Bon, Rai
...hand me the number six Torx screwdriver.
passe-moi le tournevis numéro 6.
Stop.
Arrête.
We can't do this. It's not right.
C'est mal de faire ça.
Sheldon. you have got two choices.
Sheldon, on a deux possibilités.
Put a bigger hard drive in the TiVo or delete stuff before we go out of town.
Augmenter l'espace de TiVo ou tout effacer avant de partir.
But once you open the box. you've voided the warranty.
Mais une fois la boîte ouverte, en perd la garantie.
The warranty is a sacred covenant we've entered into with the manufacturer.
C‘est une alliance sacrée avec le fabricant.
He offers to stand by his equipment.
Il offre le SAV,
We in return agree not to violate the integrity of the internal hardware.
et nous acceptons de ne pas violer l‘intégrité du disque dur.
This little orange sticker is all that stands between us and anarchy.
Cet autocollant orange fait frontière entre nous et l‘anarchie.
Okay. then we won't touch the hard drive.
Bon, on n'y touche pas.
We'll just erase the first season of Battlestar.
On va simplement effacer Battlestar.
There. We're outlaws.
Voilà. On est hors la loi.
-Here you go. Leonard. Is this big enough? -|t's perfect.
- Voilà, Leonard. C‘est assez gros ? - C‘est parfait.
For taking daffodils to your unicorn.
Si tu voulais ramener des jonquilles a ta licorne.
It's just for my notebooks. Thanks. Penny.
C‘est pour mes cahiers. Merci.
I love San Francisco. lwish l was going with you.
J'adore San Francisco. J'aimerais venir avec vous.
I understand your envy.
Je te comprends.
This is a can't-miss symposium.
C‘est le colloque a ne pas manquer.
There are going to be discussions on bioorganic cellular computer devices...
On parlera de l'avance des composants informatiques
...advancements in multi-threaded task completion...
bio-organiques en mode multitâches
...plus a round table on the non-equilibrium Green's Function approach...
et il y aura une table ronde sur la Fonction de Green
...to the photoionization process in atoms.
sur le processus photoionique de l'atome.
When I go. I usually just get hammered and ride the cable cars.
Moi quand j'y vais je picole et je fais des tours de cable cars.
This conference is a big thing.
C‘est une conférence importante.
The keynote address is delivered by George Smoot.
C‘est George Smoot qui l‘inaugure.
Oh. my God. The George Smoot?
Oh, mon Dieu. Le George Smoot ?
-You've heard of him? -Of course I haven't.
- Tu connais ? - Bien sûr que non.
George Smoot is a Nobel Prize-winning physicist...
George Smoot a eu le prix Nobel de physique,
...one of the great minds of our time.
il fait parti des grands.
His work in black body form...
Son travail sur le corps noir
...and anisotropy of the cosmic microwave background radiation...
et l‘anisotropie du fond diffus cosmologique
...cemented our understanding of the origin of the universe.
a cimenté la compréhension de l‘origine de l'univers.
It's kind of a funny name though.
Il a un nom marrant.
Smoot.
Smoot.
It's like talking to a chimp.
C‘est comme parler a un singe.
Okay. now that I've been completely insulted. have a good flight.
Maintenant que je me suis fait insulter, bon voi.
-Yeah. I wish. -We're not flying. We're taking the train.
- Si seulement. - On prend le train.
Oh. cool.
Cool.
Yeah. cool. Seven times as long as flying and costs almost twice as much.
C‘est ca, cool. Sept fois plus long et deux fois plus cher.
-Well then why are you doing it? -Well. we had a vote.
- Pourquoi ce choix ? - On a voté.
Three voted for airplane. Sheldon voted for train.
Trois voix pour l'avion, Sheldon pour le train.
So we're taking the train.
On prend donc le train.
Don't say it like that. Leonard. Say it like. "We're taking the train!“
Ne le dis pas comme ça, Leonard. Dis : "On prend le train !“
We're going to the Apple store to make fun of the Genius Bar.
On va se moquer du gars de l‘Apple Store.
You wanna come?
Tu Viens ?
Oh, I always enjoy that. but I'm a little busy.
Oh, je m'y amuse toujours, mais je suis occupé.
What are you doing?
Tu fais quoi ?
l'm simplifying the task of packing for our trip.
Je simplifie l'empaquetage.
See. by attaching RFID tags to my clothing...
En collant des radio—étiquettes,
...it will enable my laptop to read and identify the items with this wand.
je permettrai a mon PC de lire et identifier chaque article.
Then cross-reference them against destination...
Puis j'établirai un programme de référencement : destination,
...weather conditions. duration of trip. etc.
conditions climatiques, durée du séjour, etc.
Well. that does sound much simpler.
Ça m‘a l‘air plus simple.
How long is this gonna take?
Ça prend longtemps ?
Assuming I can keep up this pace. three hours 11 minutes.
A ce rythme, 3h11.
Plus however long it takes to conclude this fairly pointless conversation.
Plus le temps nécessaire pour terminer cette conversation inutile.
Wow.
Enquiquiner le gars de l‘Apple Store a l‘air d'un coup moins marrant.
-I don't follow. -Wou|dn't expect you to. I'll see you later.
- Je ne suis pas. - Ça me surprend pas. A plus.
Socks. one pair. cotton. argyle. blue.
Chaussettes, une paire, coton. motif losange, bleue.
What on earth are you doing?
Qu‘est—ce que tu fais ?
Whatever it is. I'm guessing we're doing it wrong.
Quoi que ce soit, je le fais mal.
Gentlemen. this is the Coast Starlight...
Messieurs, ceci est le Coast Starlight,
...one of the great American trains operating...
un des plus grands trains américains opérant sur une des routes typiques.
On this side. you'll see panoramic ocean vistas...
Par là, nous aurons une vue sur l'océan,
...inaccessible to any other form of transportation.
inaccessible a tout autre moyen de transport.
While on your side you'll be treated to 350 miles...
Alors que de ce côté, vous verrez 560 km
...of Costcos. Jiffy Lubes and cinder block homes with above-ground pools.
de quincailleries, garages autos et de maisons en parpaing.
-Come on. Raj. -What's wrong with Jiffy Lubes?
- Allez, Ra]. - C‘est quoi le probléme ?
No.
Non.
-Why not? -That's over the wheelbase.
- Pourquoi ? - C‘est au-dessus des essieux.
Are you completely unfamiliar with the suspension characteristics...
Tu n'es pas familier avec la suspension
...of a pre-1980 Pullman-built Superliner Deluxe passenger coach?
des wagons Superline Deluxe pré-1980 fabriqués par Pullman ?
Sheldon. we've been on this train 90 seconds...
Sheldon, on est la depuis 90 secondes
...and you've already said a thousand words.
et tu as déjà dit 1 000 mots.
Just tell us where to sit and shut up.
Dis-nous où nous asseoir et tais-toi.
Here.
Ici.
I'm hoping once you reap the endorphic rewards...
J‘éspère que quand savourerez le fruit endorphinique
...of the steady clickety-clack of steel wheels on polished rails...
du bruit constant des roues sur les rails
-...your sour disposition will abate. -Yeah. maybe.
- vos bougonneries s'atténueront. - Oui, peut—ètre.
Back in the 21st century. people are raising tray tables...
Au 21e siècle, les gens relèvent leurs tablettes et redressent leurs sièges
...because it's time to land in San Francisco.
quand il est l‘heure d'atterrir a San Francisco.
It's not so bad really. At least these trains have modern plumbing.
C‘est pas si mal. Au moins la tuyauterie est bonne.
In India. you squat over a hole in the train and expose your naked buttocks...
En Inde, quand vous allez aux toilettes, vous exposez vos fesses
...to the chilly air of Rajasthan.
a l‘air frisquet du Rajasthan.
He is referring. of course. to third class...
Il parle, bien sûr, dela 3e classe
...on Indian Railways' magnificent Ranakpur Express...
du magnifique Ranakpur Express
...and its 1200-kilometer journey from Maharashtra to the Bikaner Junction.
et son parcours de 1 200 km de Maharashtra a Bikaner.
Oh. look. Now he's boring on an international scale.
A présent il est ennuyeux à l‘échelle internationale.
Holy crap. look.
Merde alors, regardez.
-|s that who I think it is? -It can't be.
- C‘est qui je pense ? - Impossible.
What would Summer Glau be doing riding the train?
Qu‘est—ce que Summer Glau ferait ici ?
Maybe John Connor's aboard and she's protecting him from an evil Terminator.
Peut-être que John Connor est a bord et qu'elle le protège du Terminator.
Unlikely. That's a television show. Leonard.
J'en doute. C‘est une série, Leonard.
Thank you.
Merci.
lf Skynet did exist in the future. a perfect way to infiltrate and destroy mankind...
Si Skynet existait, la meilleure façon d‘infiltrer et de détruire l'humanité
...would be to send Terminators back as actors...
serait d‘envoyer les acteurs
...who have played Terminators in films and television...
qui ont joué des Terminators au ciné ou a la télé,
...lulling us into a false sense of security. i.e.:
nous faisant nous croire en sécurité :
“That's Summer Glau from The Sarah Connor Chronicles.
"C‘est Summer Glau des Chroniques de Sarah Gunnar.
No. Summer. don't kill me! I'm pro-robot.“
Non, Summer, ne me tue pas ! J'aime les robots ! Ah !“
At least he's off the train crap.
Au moins il en a fini avec les trains.
Sheldon. I owe you an apology.
Je te dois des excuses.
Taking the train was a stroke of brilliance. I've actually got a shot at a Terminator.
L'idée du train est brillante. Je peux tenter ma chance avec un Terminator.
Please. When it comes to Terminators...
Je t'en prie,
...you've got a better shot of scoring with Arnold Schwarzenegger.
t‘as plus de chance avec Arnold Schwarzenegger.
You're overlooking something.
Tu négligés quelque chose.
l have 11 hours with her in a confined space.
J'ai 11 h a passer avec elle dans un espace confiné.
Unless she's willing to jump off a moving train...
A moins qu'elle ne saute du train
...tuck and roll down the side of a hill. she will eventually succumb...
et qu'elle ne roule en bas dela colline, elie succombera
...to the acquired taste that is Howard Wolowitz.
au charme reconnu de Howard Wolowitz.
My money's on tuck and roll.
Je parie pour la dégringolade.
I'm confused.
Je suis confus.
I thought you were involved in some sort of...
Je pensais que tu étais engagé dans un lien intime avec Leslie Winkle.
-Let me explain to you how this works. -All right.
- Je vais t'expliquer. - Trés bien.
-That's Summer Glau. -Yes?
- C‘est Summer Glau. - Et alors ?
That's it.
C‘est tout.
Hang on a sec.
Une seconde.
-Why do you get first crack at her? -Uh. well. let's see. Couple reasons.
- Pourquoi tu serais le 1er ? - Pour plusieurs raisons.
One. I saw her first.
Une, je l'ai vue le premier.
No. you didn't. I did.
Faux. C‘est moi.
Fair enough. But then let me move on to number two.
Bon, d‘accord. Mais voilà la 2e raison.
Unlike you. I can actually talk to women when I'm sober.
Moi je peux parler aux femmes quand je suis sobre.
You fail to take into account that even mute. I am foreign and exotic...
Tu oubliés que même muet, je suis étranger et exotique
...while you. on the other hand. are frail and pasty.
alors que toi, tu es frêle et vitreux.
Well. you know the old saying.
Tu connais l'adage.
Pasty and frail. never fail.
Frêle et vitreux. toujours chanceux.
Excuse me. but what about me?
Et moi alors ?
Why don't I get a shot?
Pourquoi pas moi ?
Fine. go ahead. take a shot.
O.K, vas-y, tente ta chance.
I've already got a gorgeous blonde back home I can't score with.
J'ai déja une belle blonde avec qui ca pêché.
I think I'll let you two take this one.
Je vous laisse celle—ci.
Sheldon. is there a place on this train to get alcohol?
Sheldon, on peut prendre un verre ici ?
Interesting that you ask.
Question intéressante.
The Coast Starlight recently added the refurbished Pacific Parlour Car.
Le Coast Starlight a rajouté un wagon bar.
Built in 1956 and originally known as the Santa Fe Lounge Car. the lower level--
La Santa Fe Lounge Car construite en 1956 dont le niveau inférieur...
-Which way? -Upper level is a bar...
- Par où ? - le niveau supérieur est un bar
...that offers wine tastings if you're going as far as Portland.
qui offre des dégustations de vin.
Aren't you gonna go talk to her?
Tu vas pas lui parler ?
I will. I'm just working on my opening line.
Si, je prépare ma première réplique.
She's probably heard every possible line. Howard.
Elle a sûrement déjà tout entendu, Howard.
Why don't you try. “Hello?“
Pourquoi pas ”salut“ ?
No. no. no. That always creeps girls out.
Non, non, non. Elles aiment pas.
I need to come up with something that's funny. smart and delicately suggests...
Je dois trouver quelque chose de drôle, de malin et qui suggère
...that my sexual endowment is disproportionate to my physical stature.
que ma stature ne rend pas justice a mes atouts sexuels.
You're gonna need more than 11 hours.
Il te faudra plus de 11 heures.
Oh no.
Oh non.
-What's the matter? -I forgot my flash drive.
- Quoi ? - J'ai oublié ma clé USB.
-So? -So we have to go back.
- Alors ? - Il faut faire demi—tour.
Okay. Sheldon. I'm gonna say. "Why?“
Bon, je vais demander "Pourquoi ?“
And your answer cannot be “Because I forgot my flash drive.“
et tu ne pourras pas répondre “Parce que j'ai oublié ma clé USB.“
You don't understand.
Je ne saisis pas.
My flash drive has my paper on astrophysical probes...
J‘y ai mon article sur les ondes astrophysiques
...of M-theory effects in the early universe...
des effets de la théorie M
...l was gonna give to George Smoot at the conference.
que je voulais donner à George Smoot.
Why do you have to give your paper to George Smoot?
Pourquoi tu voulais lui donner ton article ?
lt's brilliant. He needs to read it.
C‘est brillant. Il doit le lire.
So you'll send him an email when we get back.
Tu lui renverras par e-mail.
Then I won't get to see his face light up as he reads it.
Mais je ne pourrai pas voir sa tête quand il le lira.
-Right. Of course. -Oh. this is an unmitigated disaster.
- Bien sûr. - C‘est un vrai désastre.
Well, there's nothing you can do about it. so relax.
Tu n‘y peux plus rien, alors relaxé.
Sit back. enjoy the clickety-clack of the steel wheels on the polished rails.
Détends-toi, apprécie le cliquetis des roues sur les railles.
[SINGING] You forgot your ﬂash drive You forgot your ﬂash drive
Tu as oublié ta clé USB
Only 10 hours. 55 minutes to go.
Plus que 10h55.
It's hot in here. Must be Summer.
Il fait chaud. Ça doit être l'été.
So. where you gals headed?
Alors les ﬁlles, vous allez où ?
Okay. I've found the perfect solution.
J'ai trouvé la solution.
We get off the train at the next stop in Oxnard.
On descend à Oxnard, le prochain arrêt.
We then take the 1:13 train back to Union Station.
On prend le train de 13h13 pour Union Station.
We take a cab back. get my flash drive...
On prend un taxi, récupère ma clé,
...and race to San Luis Obispo. assuming the lights are with us. minimal traffic...
on fonce jusqu‘à San Luis Obispo, et si on a tous les feux,
...we'll meet the train.
on tombera sur le train.
-|'ve got a better idea. -Are you going to be sarcastic?
- J'ai une meilleure idée. - Tu vas jouer du sarcasme ?
Boy. you take all the fun out of it for me.
Mince, tu m‘enléves tout mon plaisir.
But. look. Penny's home.
Penny est chez elle.
Why don't we call her. have her get your flash drive and e-mail you the paper?
Appelle—la, qu'elle t'envoie l‘article par e-mail.
But the flash drive is in a locked drawer in my desk.
Mais ma clé est enfermée dans un tiroir.
-So? -The key is hidden in my room.
- Alors ? - La clé est dans ma chambre.
-Penny'd have to go into my room.
- Penny devrait y entrer.
-So? -People don't go in my room.
- Alors ? - Personne n‘y entré.
I see. Well. it seems once again...
Je vois. On dirait qu'à nouveau
...you're caught between a rock and a crazy place.
tu te retrouves à devoir faire un choix cornélien.
Oh. I hate when that happens.
Je déteste quand ca arrive.
It's hot in here. Must be Summer. It's hot in here. Must be summer.
Il fait chaud. Ça doit être l'été.
-That's cute. -Really? I just made it up.
- C‘est mignon. - Je Viens de l‘inventer.
Have you seen Slumdog Millionaire?
Vous avez vu Slumdug Milliunaire ?
Oh yeah. I loved it.
Je l'ai adoré.
It's loosely based on my life.
C‘est basé sur ma vie.
We're putting the play on for one night in this little 99-seat theater.
On ne joue qu'un soir, il y a 99 places.
Can you come? Oh. great.
Tu peux venir ? Super.
Do you know 98 other people that might wanna come?
Tu connais 98 personnes susceptibles de venir ?
Oh. hang on. Hello?
Oh, un instant. Allô ?
Listen. I'm about to give you a set of instructions...
Ecoute, je vais te donner des instructions
...which you must follow to the letter.
a suivre a la lettre.
Just a sec.
Une seconde.
Theater's above a bowling alley so it's a little noisy...
Le théâtre est au-dessus d'un bowling,
...but it might be the only chance I'll ever get to play Anne Frank.
mais c‘est peut-être ma seule chance de jouer Anne Frank.
And the director is brilliant.
Le metteur en scène est génial.
He uses the bowling sounds as. like. Nazi artillery.
Il utilise les bruits du bowling pour l'artillerie des Nazis.
Okay. great. I'll see you then.
Génial, on s‘y voit alors.
-He||o? SHELDON: Okay, step Iour.
- Allô ? - Etape 4.
Do you see that small plastic case on my dresser?
Tu vois la boite en plastique dans ma commode ?
Your dresser? Who is this?
Ta commode ? C‘est qui ?
It's Sheldon.
- C‘est Sheldon. - Hé, Sheldon. Alors, San Francisco ?
I'm not in San Francisco. I'm on a tra-- Were you even listening to me?
Je n‘y suis pas. Je suis dans Ie tr... Tu m'écoutais ?
No. I was talking to my friend. What's up?
Non. Quoi de neuf ?
What's up? I'll tell you what's up.
Je vais te dire moi.
I'm in a crisis situation...
C‘est la crise
...I need you to marshal your powers of concentration. limited as they may be--
et j'ai besoin de ta capacité à te concentrer, aussi limitée soit—elle...
Give me the phone.
Donne—moi le téléphone.
Hi. Penny. it's Leonard.
Penny, c‘est Leonard.
Hey. Leonard. what's going on with Dr. Wackadoodle?
Hé, Leonard, qu'est-ce que veut le Dr. Maboul ?
He's calling to ask you a favor. You might be confused...
Il a besoin d'un service. C‘est déstabilisant
...because he didn't use the words “Penny." "Sheldon." “please“ or “favor.“
parce qu'il n‘a pas utilisé les mots Penny, s'il te plait ou service.
Okay. Enough chitchat.
D‘accord.
Okay. step one: Locate your emergency key to our apartment.
Etape 1 : Trouver la clé de notre appartement.
Step two: Enter our apartment. Step three....
Etape 2 : Pénétrer dans notre appartement. Etape 3 :
Enter my bedroom.
Entrer dans ma chambre.
SHELDON: Step four-- -Yeah. hang on. getting another call.
- Etape 4... - Attends, j'ai un double appel.
No!
Non !
Let me tell you something. Personal robots cannot get here soon enough.
Je vais te dire. Vivement les robots domestiques.
And that bright little star peeking her head out early today...
Et cette étoile brillante qui pointe si tôt son nez,
...that's Venus.
c‘est Vénus.
That is so cool.
C‘est vraiment génial.
You know a lot about space.
Tu t'y connais en espace.
Come on. When you were on TV in Fireﬂy. you were actually in space.
Quand tu jouais dans Firefly, toi tu étais vraiment dans l‘espace.
You're not one of those guys who believe that?
Tu n‘y crois pas vraiment ?
You mean one of the hopeless geeks? No.
Comme ces geeks désespérés ? Non.
Those are crazy people.
Eux, c‘est des cinglés.
Howard. be a dear and get me another one of these.
Howard, sois un chou et va m'en chercher une autre.
Now him. he's one of those geeks.
Lui par contre, c‘est un de ces geeks.
All right. now before you enter my bedroom unescorted...
Avant d'entrer dans ma chambre non accompagnée,
...I need you to understand that this one time grant of access...
je veux que tu comprennes que cette autorisation d‘accès
...does not create a permanent easement.
ne constitue pas un droit de passage permanent.
Easement.
Un droit.
It's a legal right of access. Good grief.
C‘est un droit de passage légal. Doux Jésus.
What? No. don't put me on hold. |-- Oh....
Quoi ? Non, ne me mets pas en attente. Je...
HOWARD: Do you believe him?
Vous l'avez vu ?
Normally around women. he has the personality of a boiled potato.
D'habitude il ala personnalité d‘une patate bouillie prés des femmes.
Put one beer in him. and he's M. Knight Charmalarmalon.
Une bière et il se transforme en Knight Çharmalamalon.
Is that what he's drinking? It's not even real beer.
C‘est ce qu'il boit ? C‘est de la fausse.
-What? -Look at it.
- Quoi ? - Regarde.
Non-alcoholic beer.
Bière non—alcoolisée.
-Then what's going on? -I don't know.
- Que se passe-t-il ? - Aucune idée.
Some sort of placebo effect. I guess.
Un effet placebo sûrement.
Placebo. you say.
Un placebo, tu dis.
Interesting.
Intéressant.
Yes. I'm still here. Where am I going? I'm on a train.
Où pourrais-je aller ? Je suis dans un train.
Now. what you'll be looking for is a small wooden box...
Maintenant, cherche une petite boite en bois
...located between a Hoberman Sphere and a sample of quartz flecked with pyrite.
qui se trouve entre une Sphère Hoberman
Hoberman Sphere.
Une Sphère Hoberman.
It's a collapsible icosidodecahedron.
C‘est un icosidodécaédre escamotable.
No. the thing with the time on it is my alarm clock. My God.
Non, le truc avec l‘heure dessus c‘est mon réveil. Mon Dieu.
Actually. in India. the names of constellations are different.
En Inde, les noms des constellations sont différents.
Where you have the Big Dipper. we have the Big Curry Pot.
La Grande Ourse s‘appelle chez nous, la Grande Casserole a Curry.
You're making that up.
Tu me fais marcher.
You got me.
Tu m'as eu.
Now. what are you going to do with me?
Qu‘est—ce que tu vas me faire ?
-Raj. Look. -Yes?
- Raj. Regarde. - Oui ?
-What am I looking at? -You tell me.
- Je regarde quoi ? - A toi de me dire.
Non-alcoholic beer.
Bière non—alcoolisée.
Hi. I'm the small package good things come in.
Salut, je suis la petite boite mais avec le beau cadeau.
Okay. I got a box. but there's no key in here. Just letters.
Bon, j'ai une boîte, mais pas de clé. Juste des lettres.
That's the wrong box. Put it back.
Mauvaise boîte. Remets-la.
Oh. Sheldon. are these letters from your grandmother?
C‘est des lettres de ta grand-mère ?
Don't read those letters.
Ne les lis pas !
Oh. look. she calls you Moon Pie. That is so cute.
Elle t'appelle mon lapin en sucre. C‘est chou.
[SHRIEKING] Put down the letters!
Repose ces lettres !
Hey. Penny. It's Leonard.
Penny. C‘est Leonard.
Hey. Leonard. How's the train ride?
Leonard. Alors, ce voyage ?
Delightful. I don't know what you're doing right now...
Délicieux. Je sais pas ce que tu fais
...but there are little bubbles forming in the corner of Sheldon's mouth.
mais une bulle se forme au coin dela bouche de Sheldon.
Okay. Yeah. I kind of crossed a line. Put him back on.
Bon, j'ai dépassé les bornes. Repasse-le-moi.
Thank you.
Merci.
-|'m back. -What up. Moon Pie?
- C‘est moi. - Alors, lapin en sucre ?
No one calls me Moon Pie but Meemaw.
Il n‘y a que Maminou qui m‘appelle comme ca !
Hey. Penny. Leonard again.
Penny. C‘est encore Leonard.
So anyway. in the dream. you and I were ice skating. just the two of us.
Donc, dans le rêve, on faisait du patin à glace.
And then I picked you up by your ankles...
Je t'ai attrapée par les chevilles
...and twirled you round and round until your legs tore off.
pour te faire tournoyer jusqu‘à ce que tes jambes s'arrachent.
I mean. I tried to stick them back on. but before I could...
J'ai essayé de les rattacher mais avant de pouvoir
...you turned into a giant loaf of pumpernickel bread.
tu t‘es transformée en un gigantesque pain de seigle.
What do you think that means?
Oué! sens ca a ?
I really don't know.
Je ne sais vraiment pas.
I'll give you a little clue.
Je vais te donner un indice.
My favorite sandwich? Salami on pumpernickel.
Mon sandwich préféré ? Salami sur pain de seigle.
Is that so?
Vraiment ?
Did you know the word pumpernickel comes...
Tu sais qu'en anglais on dit “pimpernickel“. Ça Vient de l‘allemand.
Which loosely translates to fart goblin?
Tu savais que ca signifiait pet de gnome ?
No. I didn't.
Non, je ne le savais pas.
Okay. I found the box. Now what?
J'ai trouvé la boîte, aprés ?
You're holding a Japanese puzzle box. which takes 10 precise moves to open.
Il faut 10 mouvements précis pour ouvrir cette boite de jeux japonaise.
Okay. first locate the panel with the diamond pattern...
D'abord, localise le panneau en forme de losange
...and slide the center portion 1 millimeter to the left.
et fais glisser la partie centrale d‘1 mm vers la gauche.
Then. on the opposite end of the box...
Puis du côté opposé,
...slide the entire panel down 2 millimeters.
fais glisser le panneau entier de 2 mm vers le bas.
You'll hear a slight click.
Tu entendras un petit click.
Hang on. Sheldon. do you have any emotional attachment to this box?
Attends. Tu éprouves un attachement affectif pour cette boite ?
No. It's a novelty I ordered off the Internet. Did you hear the click?
Non. C‘est juste un bibelot. Tu as entendu le click ?
Not yet.
Pas encore.
There it is.
C‘est fait.
Okay. here's another one.
Ecoute ca.
If you married the famous rock guitarist Johnny Winter...
Si tu épousais le célèbre guitariste de rock Johnny Winter
...you'd be Summer Winter.
tu t‘appellerais Summer Winter.
Okay. I'm gonna just go for broke here and say I like you.
Je vais simplement tenter ma chance et te dire que je t'aime bien.
Yeah?
Ah oui ?
So here's my question:
Je me demandais :
Do you see any conversational path that would take us from where we are now...
Est-ce que tu penses qu'on pourrait en arriver a un point
...to a place where I could ask you out and you'd say yes?
où tu accepterais une invitation à sortir ?
No.
Non.
Fair enough. I'll leave you in peace.
Bon d‘accord. Je te laisse tranquille.
Thank you.
Merci.
But before I go...
Mais avant de partir,
...would you mind if I just take one picture of us together for my Facebook page?
ca t'ennuie si je prends une photo de nous pour ma page Facebook ?
Sure.
Je t'en prie.
Okay. Great.
O.K. Super.
Can I take one where it looks like we're making out?
On pourrait feindre de s‘embrasser ?
Okay. now you're going to insert the flash drive into the USB port.
Bon, maintenant, tu insérés la clé dans le port USB.
She calls me Moon Pie because I'm nummy-nummy...
Elle m‘appelle lapin en sucre parce que je suis chou
...and she could just eat me up.
et qu'elle pourrait me manger.
Now please put the flash drive in the USB port.
A présent, insère la clé dans le port USB, s'il te plaît.
The one that looks like a little duck's mouth.
Celui qui ressemble a un bec de canard.
-Hey. how'd it go? -Terminator broke my phone.
- Comment ca s‘est passé ? - Terminator a pété mon téléphone.
Excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
Okay. I'll be honest with you.
Je vais être honnête.
I've spent the last two hours imagining various scenarios in my head...
J'ai passé 2 h a me faire des films,
...trying to come up with some line to say to you...
a essayer de trouver la réplique parfaite,
...but then I finally realized you're a human being. I'm a human being.
puis j'ai réalisé qu'on est tous les deux des êtres humains.
I could just say--
- Je pourrais... -Pruchain arrêt, Santa Barbara.
I'm sorry. This is me.
Désolée, je descends la.
“Hi. my name's Leonard.“
Salut, je m‘appelle Leonard.
So I'm thinking you won the Nobel Prize. what. three years ago...
Vous avez obtenu le Prix Nobel, il y a, quoi, 3 ans.
...so you must deal with a whole lot of “What has Smoot done lately?“
on doit souvent vous demander “Et depuis ?“
My thought is we continue my research as a team. you know...
On pourrait continuer mes recherches en équipe,
...Cooper-Smoot. alphabetical...
Cooper-Smoot. alphabétiquement
...and when we win the Nobel Prize. you'll be back on top.
et quand on remportera le Prix Nobel, vous serez à nouveau au top.
With all due respect. Dr. Cooper. are you on crack?
Dr Cooper, vous avez pris du crack ?
Fine. Smoot-Cooper.
Bon. Smoot-Cooper.
Wow. what a diva.
Quelle diva !
[ENGLISH SDH]
[FRENCH]